OPERATIONS AND TRAINING/HR DIRECTOR

Summary

Profile: HR Business Partner Outstanding track record of transforming human resource units into cost efficient strategic entities and valued partners in attaining top-priority business growth. *Innovative HR Business Partner with 10+ years' experience across diverse industries to include manufacturing, restaurants, non-profit and telecommunications. Deep expertise across all HR disciplines. *Genuine influencer translating business vision into strategic HR initiatives, processes and programs supporting core business strategy. Drives HR functional excellence and process improvements in executing people initiatives. *Talented team builder and coach providing consultation and guidance to management and senior leaders in the interpretation of human resource policies and procedures, and application of related government laws and regulations. *MBA educated leader with keen business acumen and strong strategic-planning, recruitment, employee relations and project management skills; delivers results, creates value for brands, customers and key stakeholders. *Outstanding corporate ambassador, who serves as the ultimate change agent and cultural champion.

Skills

- Performance Management
- Onboarding Programs
- HR Metrics, & Reporting
- Talent Acquisition
- Staff Training & Coaching
- Talent Management
- Best Practices
- Retention Strategies
- Safety and Security
- Conflict Resolution
- Organizational Development
- Talent Management
- Training and Development
- Organizational Development
- Needs Analysis

Experience

Operations and Training/HR Director Jan 2017 to Jul 2017 Community Action Program For Central Arkansas i¹/₄ Amite, LA

- Served as temporary acting owner for a full-scale health and fitness club with 800+ members.
- Led full-scale operation during owner absence.
- Accountable for human resources, member experience, employee training and development, accounting, finance, and budget operations, along with marketing, sales and advertising.
- Needs Analysis: Identified gaps within policy communication and operational processes impacting member retention.
- Proactively implemented employee relations and communications programs to restore credibility between members and staff.
- Reduced turnover by 20% within 1st quarter of 2017 through visible leadership, along with coaching and accountability sessions with staff.

Human Resources Director Oct 2015 to Mar 2017

Asml N.V. ï1/4 San Jose, CA

- 119-year-old golf and country club.
- 20 M revenue.
- 450 employees.
- 1860 members Trusted member of executive team and strategic business partner.
- One direct report.
- Envisioned and implemented strategic leadership and consultation services, partnering with leaders to improve employee retention, organizational performance, individual and professional growth.
- HR Leadership: Directed HR operations for over 450 employees to include employee relations, recruiting and selection, performance
 management, talent acquisition, benefits administration, training, engagement, employee communications, safety, legal and regulatory
 compliance programs.
- Developed and implemented the "RISE Recognition program" which recognized individuals who demonstrated core values through behaviors and actions.
- Extensive values based work led to early adoption.
- Internship Program Assisted in the rollout of the first hospitality internship program, along with introducing a successful referral program.
- Improved orientation to include new hire required OSHA mandated training.
- Policy/Process Standardization: Instituted a formalized recruitment and selection process with an emphasis on compliance, consistency, and standardization.
- Efforts resulted in progressively lower turnover.
- Change Management: Led change management strategy for launch of new core values identified by senior staff.
- Orchestrated six kickoff sessions, new leader led video, rewards and recognition program, logo and newsletter.
- Recruiting and Selection: Job board transition for hourly posted positions thus increasing the quality and quantity of qualified candidates;
 referral program implementation and college internship program.

- HR Consultation and Support: Employed methods to coach, mentor and counsel management on performance management guidelines, employee relations issues, individual accountability, along with policy implementation and interpretation.
- Scheduled consistent 1:1 meetings advancing a "leader" mindset.
- Training and Development: Developed and launched an in-house training and development program.
- Mentored a high performing employee into a new role to oversee the program advancing a "culture of continuous learning.".
- Curriculum Development: Designed and presented management-training programs ranging from first-line leaders to senior- management teams to facilitate understanding of employment relations, and performance management.
- Employee Communication Portal: Spearheaded the development and launch of a new employee communication portal, a one-stop resource allowing employees to download company policies, benefits information.
- Portal improved communications, streamlined workflow and increased employee engagement.

Human Resources Director / Human Resources Manager Apr 2013 to Oct 2015 Atlanta Bread Company / Bakeone Inc Atlanta Bread Company i1/4 City , STATE

- Fast casual bakery café.
- 40 cafes.
- 10M revenue.
- 200 employees.
- Bakeone, Inc.
- 120,000 sq.
- foot industrial manufacturing bakery.
- 30M revenue.
- 200 employees Recruited to revamp HR operations for a \$30M Manufacturing Bakery Company and a \$10M multi-unit restaurant operation.
- Served on the executive team reporting to the CEO and CAO with one direct report.
- HR Leadership: Directed all facets of the HR function for two sister companies to include training, employee relations, engagement, benefits administration, payroll, recruiting and performance management.
- Served as benefits administrator, 401K trustee and safety committee lead.
- Recruiting Expertise: Slashed recruitment/temp agency fees by \$250K in year one by revamping recruitment; transitioned to an in-house function.
- Relocated top talent to run \$2M state of the art equipment.
- HR Consultation and support: Facilitated monthly workshops for management teams in all CafAC's.
- Advised and counseled management regarding upcoming legislation regarding ACA and FLSA.
- HR Metrics and Reporting: Collaborated with senior executives to assess financial health of manufacturing operations through key metrics, reporting and trend analysis.
- Wal-Mart Supplier audit: Served as safety audit lead for our Wal-Mart supplier audit (BakeOne's largest revenue producing customer) thus achieving the highest ranking to be awarded based on a comprehensive safety inspection.
- Line Level Engagement: Engaged line leads on all three shifts, providing each with a "Memo to Managers," notebook; served as a guide to study prior to informal 1:1 trainings.
- Regulatory Compliance Led, designed and delivered training programs on drug and alcohol awareness, harassment and respect, performance management and OHSA safety training requirements.
- Safety: Instituted the first formal safety committee and OSHA approved safety manual.
- Achieved full compliance within the 120,000-sq.
- foot manufacturing facility.
- Employment La Accomplished compliant investigations through proven skills in labor and employment law to thwart legal action; served as legal point of contact.
- HR Audits: Initiated a benefit billing audit, uncovering 100K in previous overbilled vendor fees.
- Spearheaded an I-9 compliance audit and job description audit and review.
- Performance Management: Spearheaded the first formal performance management program, "Path to Productivity." Program established a
 yearly planning framework and served to strengthen the employee/manager relationship through coaching, goal setting, career and individual
 developmental sessions.

Human Resources Director / Human Resources Manager Nov 2011 to Nov 2012 JGI Consulting i $^1\!/_4$ City , STATE

- International management consulting firm providing in construction, architecture and environmental services.
- Recruited by a successful international entrepreneur.
- Led the startup and management of a full spectrum of HR operations, systems and programs for a highly visible Emirates Airlines design build project.
- Reported to the owner and CEO with a line to the CFO.
- Short lived start-up within Atlanta operation due to financial constraints.
- HR Policies and Procedures: Coordinated creation and maintenance of all HR policies and services.
- Established and administered all guidelines, concerning compensation, payroll, and benefits.
- Recruiting: Recruited a staff of 15 within a two-week time frame.
- Positions consisted of architects, designers and construction superintendents.
- Orientation and onboarding: Designed a comprehensive orientation and onboarding program for all new hires.

Trainer/ Project Lead Aug 2008 to Sep 2011 Stratix Corporation i¹/₄ City, STATE

- Telecommunications mobile technology and hand-held computers.
- 14M revenue.
- 150 employees Promoted to a Training/Project Lead assigned to the mobility handheld/inventory control project for the Dr.
- Pepper Snapple Group.
- 2+ year 100% travel project; visiting up to 200 facilities; a \$150M initiative.
- Training and Facilitation: Directed over 20 training specialists in the deployment of hardware and application instruction, technical support, software upgrades, and best practices.
- Conducted over 60 classes for both beverage salesmen and drivers.
- Project Management Excellence: Presented with the yearly "Values and Vision" Award at the company awards luncheon for excellence in project management during the Dr.
- Pepper Snapple deployment resulting in additional business for the company.

Benefits Manager Sep 2005 to Aug 2008 Ryan's Restaurant Group il/4 City, STATE

- Nationwide buffet-style restaurant group Recruited to design and administer corporate benefit plans and programs for over 23,000 employees within 340 restaurants in 23 states.
- Two direct reports.

Education and Training

Masters of Business Administration , Human Resource Management Georgia State University il/4 City , State Human Resource Management Bachelors of Business Administration , Finance Valdosta State University il/4 City , State Finance Activities and Honors

Human Resources Certificate / PHR Preparation, Kennesaw State University SHRM, Society for Human Resource Management ATD, Association for Talent Development Vistage Executive Group Member, WorldatWork, The Professional Association for Compensation, Benefits and Total Rewards Stratix Corporation Values & Vision Award ESL - English as Second Language Teacher night instructor - Holy Innocents School

Skills

ACA, accounting, advertising, art, agency, benefits administrator, benefits administration, billing, budget, Change Management, coach, Coaching, compliance audit, hardware, Conflict Resolution, Consultation, Curriculum Development, drivers, employee communications, employee relations, employee training, Staff Training, entrepreneur, senior- management, Fast, finance, financial, frame, goal setting, human resources, HR, inspection, instruction, interpretation, inventory control, Leadership, law, legal, Regulatory Compliance, logo, management consulting, management-training, marketing, meetings, mentor, Needs Analysis, newsletter, Organizational Development, organizational, payroll, Performance Management, Policies, processes, producing, program implementation, Project Lead, Project Management, quality, Recruiting, recruitment, reporting, Safety, sales, strategy, strategic, technical support, Telecommunications, training programs, trend, upgrades, video, Vision, workflow, workshops